你得试试这块芝士蛋糕
You have got to try this cheesecake.
我不是那么喜欢吃甜食
You know, I'm not that much of a sweet tooth...
天啊  好香浓
Oh, my God, it's so creamy!
那是我吃过最棒的芝士蛋糕
That's the best cheesecake I've ever had!
你在哪里买
Where did you get this?
我回家时它就已经放在门口了
It was at the front door when I got home.
有人寄给我们的
Somebody sent it to us.
你不是收件人
This isn't addressed to you.
收件人是楼下的布雷曼太太
This is addressed to Mrs. Braverman downstairs!
小偷
Thief!
我没看收件人姓名就打开了盒子
I didn't read the box before I opened it...
盒子已经打开了就无法退还
...and you can't return a box after you opened it!
-为什么  -因为太好吃了
- Why not? - Because it's too delicious!
你偷了人家的蛋糕  这是不对的
You stole this cheesecake. That's wrong.
不  没关系的
No, it'll be okay
因为布雷曼太太会免费再收到一个
because Mrs. Braverman will send away for a free one.
那可是双赢
That way, we all win.
唯一的输家是大型芝士蛋糕店
The only losers are the big cheesecake conglomerate...
"小妈妈的面包店"
..."Mama's Little Bakery."
我觉得好难过
I feel terrible.
我是个大坏蛋
I'm a horrible, horrible person.
我很抱歉  什么
I'm sorry, what?
我得走了  我今天工作很忙
I should get going. Big day at work.
你们知道我怎么会昏迷不醒吗
You know how I'm in a coma?
今天他们帮我做检查  结果发现我没有脑死
Today they do a test on me and it turns out I'm not brain-dead.
所以
So...
机灵鬼先生
Mr. Smarty Pants.
是我演的角色没有脑死
It's just my character that's not brain-dead.
菲比  今晚的事没取消吧
Pheebs, still on for tonight?
-没啊  -那8点见
- Absolutely. - I'll see you at 8.
8点要干嘛
What's at 8?
我和乔伊有约
We have dinner plans with Joey.
我们一月聚一次  八卦一下剩下的人
We get together about once a month to discuss the rest of you.
我还真的不知道
Wow! Did not know that.
我能说你今天看起来很漂亮吗
May I say how lovely you look today?
注意到了啊
Duly noted.
明天
So for tomorrow,
你要租辆车一起开过去吗
do you want to rent a car and drive down together?
你在说什么
What are you talking about?
芬妮表妹的婚礼  明晚
Cousin Frannie's wedding. Tomorrow night.
你被邀请了
You were invited?
没啊
No.
天啊  我简直不敢相信
Oh, my God, I can't believe this.
我以为他们只邀请了爸跟妈
I thought only Mom and Dad were invited.
七岁到九岁  芬妮跟我形影不离
From the ages of 7 to 9, Frannie and I were inseparable.
或许九岁后  芬妮交了新朋友
Maybe since the age of 9, Frannie's made some new friends.
大概是误会吧  我去给雪儿阿姨打电话
It's probably just a mistake. Let me call Aunt Cheryl.
或许他们邀请你了  只是请贴寄丢了
Maybe you are invited and the invitation got lost in the mail.
你可以打电话告诉她  我们小时候
You call her and tell her that when we were kids...
她的宝贝芬妮好几次想脱光我的衣服
...her precious Frannie tried to undress me several times.
要不是我阻止了她  她也结不了婚
If I hadrt stopped her, there wouldn't be a wedding to go to.
她也想脱我的衣服
She tried to undress me too.
我以前会帮葛兰表弟脱衣服
I used to undress my cousin Glenn.
乔瑟夫·弗朗西斯·崔比安尼  你回家了吗
Joseph Francis Tribbiani, are you home yet?
我想他还没有回家  怎么了
I think he's still out. What's wrong?
我告诉你  瑞秋·凯伦·格林
I'll tell you, Rachel Karen Greene.
我跟乔伊有约  他留了这张字条给我
I had plans with Joey, and he left me this note.
"菲比  去不了了  有约会  再聊"
"Pheebs, can't make it. Got a date. Talk to you later.
"老爹"
Big Daddy."
-"老爹"  -最近我们在试这个昵称
- "Big Daddy"? - That's a nickname we were trying out.
你知道永不会重复的昵称是什么吗
You know what nickname never caught on?
"罗斯原子人"
"The Ross-a-tron."
约瑟夫·弗兰斯西回来了
Here's Joseph Francis!
你叫我中间名做什么
Wait, what are you middle-naming me for?
我留条了
I left you a note.
那不是放我鸽子的好理由
That doesn't give you the right to ditch me!
如果你有机会打炮
You can cancel plans
当然可以取消跟朋友的约会
with friends if there's a possibility for sex.
他说的对  这是规则
He's right. That is the rule.
我不接受这规则
I don't accept it this rule.
我们约好后  我期待你会出现
When we make plans, I expect you to show up.
我不是你泡到妞前打发时间的代替品
I'm not a way to kill time till you meet someone better.
男女朋友来来去去
Boyfriends and girlfriends will come and go,
但朋友是一辈子的
but this is for life.
我很抱歉  我不知道这对你来说那么重要
I'm so sorry. I had no idea it would bother you this much.
是很重要
Well, it does.
我能弥补吗
Well, can I make it up to you?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
明晚一起吃饭  我可以为自己付账
How about dinner tomorrow night? I'll pay for myself.
好吧  你说服了我
Okay, you wore me down.
既然你在那边  拿瓶啤酒给"罗斯原子人"
While you're over there, how about a beer for "The Ross-a-tron"?
"罗斯..."  那名字又回来了
"Ross..." Is that back?
又有芝士蛋糕
The other cheesecake came.
他们又把它送到这里来
They delivered it here again.
把它送到楼下去  有什么问题
Just bring it downstairs. What's the problem?
我不知道该怎么说再见
I can't seem to say goodbye.
你认真的吗
Are you serious?
两天前我们吃掉一整个蛋糕  你还想再吃
We ate an entire cake two days ago and you want more?
我已经忘记它的味道了
Well, I've forgotten what it tastes like.
是芝士蛋糕  很好吃
It was cheesecake. It was fine.
饼干底很酥软  又香又浓
It had a buttery, crumbly, graham cracker crust...
外加上浓郁的
...with a very rich...
但不油腻的轻奶油芝士
...yet light cream cheese filling.
我口水直下三千尺啊
Wow, my whole mouth just filled with saliva.
你知道吗  忘了它  我们只是饿了
Know what? Forget it. We're just hungry.
我们没有吃午餐  所以头昏脑胀
We haven't had lunch. We're just lightheaded.
我们去吃午餐  忘了那个芝士蛋糕吧
So let's go have lunch and forget about the cheesecake.
我们得把它还回去  才不会被诱惑
We'll drop it downstairs so we're not tempted.
想去哪吃
Where do you want to eat?
小妈妈面包店  伊利诺伊州芝加哥
Mama's Little Bakery, Chicago, Illinoise.
梅尔·多米死了
Mel Torme died.
乔伊  那是一年前的报纸
Joey, that paper's like a year old.
那就说明山姆杂货铺的大减价也结束了
Does that mean the Sam Goody's sale is over?
雪儿阿姨那边有回音了
So I finally heard back from Aunt Cheryl...
很显然这不是误会
...and apparently it wasn't a mistake.
座位很有限
There's limited seating...
座位有限  我这么瘦小
Limited seating? I am just one tiny person!
对  但是她不知道
Yeah, but she doesn't know that.
她看到你
I mean, the last time she saw you...
你会把
...you'd have turned one
婚礼用的小椅子压垮
of those little wedding chairs into kindling.
"座位有限"  真是个烂借口
"Limited seating." That's such a lame excuse.
那不是她不邀请我的原因
That's not the reason she's not inviting me.
有什么大不了的呢
What's the big deal?
我没办法观礼  只能去吃喜酒
I wasn't invited to the ceremony, just the reception.
如果能让你好受点的话
If it makes you feel any better,
琼恩和我出现下
Joan and I will just make an appearance...
就提早离开  以示抗议好了
...and then we'll leave early as a sign of protest.
-琼恩  -琼恩·泰德雷斯基  我的女伴
- Joan? - Yeah, Joan Tedeschi, my date.
语言学助理教授  又高又漂亮
Assistant professor in linguistics. Tall, very beautiful.
大家都说  别找太魁梧的女孩嘛
And despite what some people say, not broad-backed.
等一下  你收到的喜贴是"请携伴参加"
Wait a minute. You got "Ross Geller and Guest"?
我没有被邀请  你却可以"携伴参加"
I wasn't invited, and you got "and Guest"?
我得代表罗斯解释一下
Excuse me, I do have to interrupt on Ross' behalf.
规则也在这里适用
I think the rule applies here.
既然他能和魁梧的姑娘嘿咻
Since he has a chance to get on broad-back...
才不魁梧
Not broad-back!
慢着  你要带我去
Wait a minute. You're bringing me.
我不能放琼恩鸽子
I can't cancel on Joan.
-为什么  -你没听我说话吗
- Why not? - Did you not hear me?
她是语言学的助理教授
She's an assistant professor in the linguistics department.
他们很狂野的
They're wild.
-你为什么想去呢  -因为
- Why do you want to come anyway? - Because...
她是我表妹
...she's my cousin.
我们一起长大
I mean, we grew up together.
我们是家人  你知道吗  那对我来说很重要
Family, you know? And all that's important to me.
好吧  我带你去
Okay, all right. I'll take you.
我去给琼恩打电话
I'll go call Joan.
真好啊
Oh, that's nice.
家人应该要出席的
Family should be there.
她的婚礼是她一生中最快乐的日子
It's her wedding. Happiest day of her life.
走着瞧
We'll see.
谢谢你请我吃午餐
Well, thank you for lunch.
等一下  我没付钱  我以为你付了钱
Wait, I didn't pay, I thought you paid.
很明显 我们不必再掏钱买食物了
Apparently, we don't pay for food anymore.
-我没有看错吧  -它还在那里
- Do you see what I see - It's still there.
布雷曼太太一定是出去了
Mrs. Braverman must be out.
她可能出城去了或许几月后才会回来
She could be out of town. Maybe gone for months.
那时蛋糕一定坏了  怎么能让她吃坏蛋糕呢
By then, it may spoil. She can't come back to bad cheesecake.
-她可能会死掉  -我不希望发生那种事
- It could kill her. - Don't want that.
我们是在保护她
We're protecting her.
-我们把它拿走  -但是快一点
- We'll take it. - But quick.
-为什么  -我听到她在里面走动的声音
- Why? - I hear her in there.
行动
Go! Go! Go!
天啊  那是大卫
Oh, my God, that's David.
-谁  -大卫  那个科学家
- Who? - David, the scientist guy.
我们之前坠入爱河了
David that I was in love with.
后来他去了俄罗斯伤了我的心  大卫
Who went to Russia and broke my heart, David.
我的天啊
Oh, my God!
只要一直念某人的名字  那个人就会转过来
Say their name enough, they turn around.
菲比
Phoebe.
大卫
David.
你在做什么  你不是在俄罗斯吗
What are you doing? Aren't you supposed to be in Russia?
我回来开会
I'm just in town for a conference.
天啊  你看起来美得出奇
God, you look phenomenal.
就
Well...
没错
Yeah.
你气色也不错  剪头发了
You look great too. Did you get a haircut?
对  剪了大概30次吧
Yeah. Well, I got like 30 of them.
我得跟你坦诚一件事
Look, I got a confession to make.
我希望能在这里遇到你
I was hoping to run into you here.
我不知道该不该打电话给你  我只会回来几天
I didn't know if I should call. I was only in town a few days...
我不想打扰你的生活
...and I didn't want to intrude on your life.
我真的想见你
I really wanted to see you...
但我不知道你想不想见我
...but I didn't know if you wanted to see me.
我当然想见你
Of course I would want to see you.
我常常想到你
I think about you all the time.
真的吗  我也常常想到你
Really? Because I think about you all the time.
明斯克有一座雕像让我常常想起你
There's a statue in Minsk that reminds me of you so much.
事实上那是列宁的雕像
It's actually of Lenin...
但有些角度
...but, you know, at certain angles...
你愿意今晚和我共进晚餐吗
Anyway, do you want to have dinner tonight?
好
Yes.
不
Oh, no!
-什么  -我不行
- What? - I can't.
真不敢相信我有约了  明天可以吗
I can't believe I have plans. Can you do it tomorrow?
再过几小时我就得离开 我得赶晚航班回去
No, I have to go in a few hours. I have to be on the redeye.
听着  下次你到明斯克
Listen, next time you're in Minsk...
菲比  我能跟你谈一谈吗
Phoebe? Can I talk to you for a second?
你在做什么
What are you doing?
我和乔伊有约
I have plans with Joey.
所以呢  他会理解的
So? He'll understand.
他不会的  而且这不是重点
No, he won't. And that's not even the point.
我教训他
I made a whole speech about
不该见色忘友
how you do not cancel plans with friends.
现在只因为可能是我真爱的人
And now just because, potentially, the love of my life...
从俄罗斯回来一晚
...returns from Russia for one night...
我就要改变我的信仰吗
...I should change my beliefs?
我应该改变我的信仰
I should change my beliefs!
不  如果失去了原则那么我一无所有
No. If I don't have my principles, I don't have anything.
你很坚强
You're so strong.
或者我可以和乔伊吃个快餐然后9点见大卫
Or I should rush through dinner with Joey and meet David at 9.
天啊  这太好吃了
Oh, my God, that is so good!
我吃饱了  但我知道如果我现在停下来
I'm full. And yet I know if I stop eating this...
我会后梅
...l'll regret it.
你们在吃什么
Hey, what have you got there?
那是
Oh, it's...
豆腐蛋糕  你要吃一点吗
It's tofu cake. Want some?
你今晚干什么
What are you doing tonight?
兄弟  兄弟
Dude. Dude.
抱歉
Sorry.
我和菲比有约
I got plans with Phoebe.
是吗  莫妮卡说她9点有约
Really? Monica said she had a date at 9.
-什么  今晚  -莫妮卡这么说来着
- What? Tonight? - That's what Monica said.
她刚教育过我
After that speech,
第二天晚上她就见色忘友放我鸽子
she makes a date on the same night she has plans with me?
她打算和"老爹"草草结束
She's trying to pull a fast one on Big Daddy.
这里  我觉得我们应该坐这里
Here, I think this is us.
座位有限个屁啊
Limited seating, my ass.
看看是谁缩减的人员
Let's see who made the cut.
我是莫妮卡·盖勒
Hi. I'm Monica Geller.
你怎么认识新郎新娘的呢
How do you know the bride and groom?
我从前和芬妮一起工作
I used to work with Frannie.
从前一起工作  从前
Used to work with her. Used to.
我是她的亲戚却没有被邀请
I'm a relative and I didn't get invited.
我是她的血亲  血
A blood relative. Blood.
别堆着陌生人说"血"
Stop saying "Blood" to strangers.
你呢  你和快乐的新人什么关系
So how about you? How do you know the happy couple?
我们是他们的大学同学
We went to college with both of them.
现在是他们的邻居
Now we live next door.
好吧  你们没事
Okay, you're fine.
-你们要点菜了吗  -是的
- Are you guys ready? - Yes.
特调酱汁的沙拉和水
I'll have a green salad, house dressing and water's fine.
你呢  先生
And for you, sir?
慢烤鲑鱼
Yeah. This slow-roasted salmon...
到底有多慢呢
...how slow are we talking?
鲑鱼已经烤好了
It's already been roasted.
那就不要  今日推荐再说一遍
Oh, then no. Maybe I should hear the specials again.
今日推荐我们已经听3遍了
We've heard the specials three times.
烤肋排  鬼头刀鱼跟特制龙虾饺子
There's prime rib, mahi-mahi and a very special lobster ravioli.
饺子没有了
Actually, we're out of the ravioli.
那一切就都不同了
Well, that changes everything!
菲比  你之前说的对
You know what, Pheebs? You were right before.
朋友太重要了
Friends are so important.
我知道我很聪明
Yeah, I'm very wise. I know.
你知道我想要什么吗
Know what I really want?
-什么  -促膝长谈一次
- What? - Is to have a long, long talk.
让乔伊对你完全敞开心扉
You know? Get Joey out on the open road and really open him up.
-可以点菜了吗  -是的
- Any progress? - Yes.
龙虾饺子
I will have the lobster ravioli.
天啊乔伊  你是要花一辈子点菜吗
God, Joey, this is taking forever.
-急什么  -就
- What's the rush? - Well...
我有约
...I have an appointment.
很重要
And it's very important.
什么约
What is it?
就
Well...
约会
...it's a date.
-约会  -你一定是搞错了
- A date? - No, you must be mistaken,
因为你不会在和朋友有约的当晚
because you wouldn't schedule a date...
又安排去约会的
...on the same night you have plans with a friend.
别让我觉得内疚
Don't make me feel badly about this.
我就要
No, I'm gonna!
你让我因为放你鸽子去和那姑娘约会非常内疚
You made me feel really guilty about going out with that girl.
就好像我杀人放火了一样  现在你也一样
Like I did something terrible. Now you're doing the same thing.
不一样  完全不一样
It's not! It's totally different!
是和大卫  记得那个科学家大卫吗
This is with David. Remember David, the scientist guy?
他对我来说非常特别
He's very special to me.
那姑娘对我也很特别  她也是科学家
My girl the other night was special. She was a scientist too.
-是吗  -她高中毕业了
- She was? - Well, she graduated high school.
随你便
Whatever. Know what?
我没时间说服你
I don't have time to convince you.
他就回来4个小时  我现在要去见他
Because he's only here for four hours and I'm gonna go see him.
-随便  -好
- Fine! - Yeah.
你还杵在这里干什么  我说了龙虾饺子
What are you still doing here? I told you, lobster ravioli!
我就准备走了  我没想到你会来
I was about to leave. I didn't think you were coming.
我不会错过你的
I wouldn't have missed this.
我很高兴你来了
Well, I'm very glad you're here.
你是个绅士
Oh, you're such a gentleman.
走  去我家
Come on, we're going to my place.
你背着我偷偷吃芝士蛋糕
Are you eating the cheesecake without me?
只要你现在能吹出口哨  我就给你一百块
I will give you $ 100 to whistle right now.
-你怎么能背着我偷吃呢  -你要怎样
- How can you eat it without me? - What'll you do?
告诉莫妮卡或乔伊  你什么都不会说
Tell Monica or Joey? No, you'd have to tell them everything.
我们是甜食小贼  我们不受法律掌控
We're dessert stealers. We're living outside the law.
我不能让你跟芝士蛋糕独处
I don't trust you with this cake.
我先发现它的  我要把它拿回来
I got it first, and I'm taking it back!
-什么  不  -我就要
- What? Oh, no. - Oh, yes.
你以为我就能相信你吗
You think I trust you with it?
平分  你一半我一半
No, we'll split it. You take an half, I take an half.
那不公平  你已经吃掉一点了
That's not fair. You had some.
我想莫妮卡一定想知道
I think Monica would be very interested to know...
你说她做的芝士蛋糕"又干又粗"
...that you called her cheesecake "Dry and mealy."
我们要用什么来切蛋糕
What do we use to split it?
好了  挑一块
All right, pick a half.
这块看上去比较大
Well, this side looks bigger.
但这块饼干比较多
But there's more crust on this side.
或者我该量一下
Maybe if I measure it...
快挑一块
Oh for god sake, just pick a piece!
-好吧  我挑那一块  -那一块比较小
- All right, I pick that one. - It's the smaller piece.
行了  就这样
Okay. There you go.
好好享受你那一半 朋友  因为大势己定
Enjoy your half, my friend. But that is it.
不分不换  别哭着找我
No sharing, no switching, and don't come crying to me...
要是你太快把那一半吃光了的话
...if you eat your piece too fast.
-你会分我点吗  -不会
- You gonna give me some of your piece? - Oh, no.
不分不换  别哭着找我
No switching, no sharing. And don't come crying to me.
我就要坐在这里  整天吃我的蛋糕
I may just sit here and have my cake all day.
坐在走廊里  吃我的
Just sit here in the hallway and eat my...
罗斯甜心
Ross, sweetheart!
米莉阿姨
Oh, hey, Aunt Millie.
-这个婚礼很温馨吧  -没错
- Isn't it a beautiful wedding? - Yes, it is.
她每次都亲嘴巴
Every time, on the lips!
为什么 为什么要亲嘴巴
Why? Why on the lips?
芬妮在那边  她看到我一定会很高兴吧
There's Frannie. Won't she be happy to see me?
你得乖乖的  好吗
Wait a minute, you be nice, all right?
我不是带你来杀她个措手不及的
I didn't bring you to ambush her.
是芬妮找到了你的《花花公子》向老妈报告的
Frannie was the one who found your Playboys and showed them to Mom.
贱人
That bitch.
莫妮卡
Monica!
你在
What...?
这里做什么  见到我惊喜吧
Am I doing here? Surprised to see me?
罗斯带我来的  你喜欢吗
Ross brought me. How do you like that?
芬妮  恭喜啊
Hi, Frannie. Congratulations.
你邀请了我哥
You invite my brother.
你邀请了我全家却不邀请我  为什么
You invite my whole family, and not me? Why?
你为什么不希望我来  我做了什么
Why wouldn't you want me here? What could I have done?
斯图尔特
Stuart!
我相信你认识我丈夫
I believe you know my husband.
问题应该是  你上了"谁"
So it's really a question of "Who" Could you have done.
我讨厌这样  但我得走了
I hate this, but I have to go.
我不能错过飞机
I can't miss my flight.
我敢说下一班飞注明斯克的飞机是在
I bet there's another flight to Minsk in...
七月
July.
那真的很好听  是什么意思
That's really beautiful. What does it mean?
"请帮我把烧杯洗干净"
"Please clean my beakers."
我不常离开实验室
I don't get out of the lab much.
我以为它有别的意思
I thought it meant something else.
事实上  我想说
Yeah, well, I really actually wanted to say...
那个
...that.
我想或许我不该说  因为
But I figured I probably shouldn't because...
我得离开
...I have to leave.
不  你说的对  别说
No, you're right. Don't say it.
但我真这么觉得
I do, though.
我也一样
I do too.
再见  菲比
Well, bye, Phoebe.
现在不是时候  乔伊 明天你可以骂我
Now's not the time, Joey. You can yell at me tomorrow.
等一下  不  菲比  我不会骂你
Wait, no, Pheebs. I'm not gonna yell at you.
我想起了你和大卫
I just started thinking about you and David...
我记得他第一次离开时你有多难过
...and I remember how bummed you were the first time he left.
菲比  过来
Oh, Pheebs, come here.
-你还好吧  -不  我一点都不好
- Are you okay? - No, I'm not okay.
我唯一喜欢的男人要去明斯克
The only guy I've ever been crazy about is going to Minsk...
或许我永远都不会再见到他
...and I may never see him again.
你可以去看他
You could always visit him.
对呢  就好像他们会给我护照一样
Right. Like they'll let me have a passport.
有什么我可以帮忙的吗  什么都行
Anything I can do? Whatever you need.
现在的话
Well, now...
如果你可以比他
...if you achieve distillation
先蒸馏出副原子粒子
of subatomic particles before he does...
他就可以回来了
...then he could come back.
我可以试试看
I could give it a shot.
你看有一小块没有沾到地板
Oh, look! There's a piece that doesn't have floor on it.
-别越界  -快点
- Stick to your side! - Come on, now!
好了  我们要吃什么
All right, what are we having?
等一下  我忘了拿披肩
Oh, wait, I forgot my wrap.
好吧  等着
All right, wait here.
甜心  你要走了吗
Hi, sweetie! Are you leaving?
-就  -快来亲阿姨一下
- Well... - Give us a kiss. Come on.
为什么  为什么要亲嘴
Why? Why on the lips?